<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Articles on Satyajit Ovelil&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/series/blog-articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog Articles on Satyajit Ovelil&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://satyajitovelil.github.io/series/blog-articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis - Part I</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis Part I: Data Visualization This is part of a series of posts that aims to capture and compile the knowledge required in order to analyse time series data. This part will take you through the basics of visualising the data.
 For your specific case, you can start by creating a line plot of your target variable over time, and then create scatter plots to explore the relationship between your target and the other independent variables that you have included after taking into consideration the potential off various factors to influence your target variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Electricity Demand Forecasting (WIP)</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/nyc-electricity-demand-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/nyc-electricity-demand-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>NYC Night Lights
   Electricity demand forecasting is a crucial task in the energy industry as it helps energy providers plan for supply and demand and avoid any potential shortage or surplus. Accurate forecasting of electricity demand can lead to better management of resources, improved operational efficiency and ultimately, cost savings. For this Project I wanted to analyze the NYC electricity demand enriched using NOAA weather data for NYC whether I could answer the following questions: What effect does date &amp;amp; time play in influencing daily electricity demand in NYC?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
