<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satyajit Ovelil&#39;s Website</title>
    <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Satyajit Ovelil&#39;s Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://satyajitovelil.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis - Part 0</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis Part 0: Data Cleaning This is part of a series of posts that aims to capture and compile the knowledge required in order to analyse time series data. This part will take you through the basics of cleaning the data.
 We are going to deal with the most common problem in time series data when it is tabular; missing rows. A mistake that all beginners make is that they check for missing values and find that there are no missing values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-sarima/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-sarima/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis Part 2: SARIMA This is part of a series of posts that aims to capture and compile the knowledge required in order to analyse time series data. This part will serve as a quick guide to analyse time series components.
 Time series analysis is a powerful technique that can help you forecast future values based on historical data. To get started, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to analyse the components of your time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis - Part I</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Time Series Analysis Part I: Data Visualization This is part of a series of posts that aims to capture and compile the knowledge required in order to analyse time series data. This part will take you through the basics of visualising the data.
 For your specific case, you can start by creating a line plot of your target variable over time, and then create scatter plots to explore the relationship between your target and the other independent variables that you have included after taking into consideration the potential off various factors to influence your target variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC Electricity Demand Forecasting (WIP)</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/nyc-electricity-demand-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/posts/nyc-electricity-demand-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>NYC Night Lights
   Electricity demand forecasting is a crucial task in the energy industry as it helps energy providers plan for supply and demand and avoid any potential shortage or surplus. Accurate forecasting of electricity demand can lead to better management of resources, improved operational efficiency and ultimately, cost savings. For this Project I wanted to analyze the NYC electricity demand enriched using NOAA weather data for NYC whether I could answer the following questions: What effect does date &amp;amp; time play in influencing daily electricity demand in NYC?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Senior Machine Learning Engineer with experience in developing, deploying and managing day-ahead, intraday and seasonal models for electricity demand forecasting, as well as designing and implementing end-to-end machine learning pipelines. Demonstrated ability to improve forecasting accuracy by 1-2 MAPE (Mean Absolute Percentage Error).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can reach me @:
 linkedIn mail +91 9175447610    Comments Policy: Comments With inappropriate or abusive content will be removed.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First snippet</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/snippets/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/snippets/first/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/first/index.md
pwd </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>NYC Electricity Demand Forecasting Summary of the project For this Project I wanted to analyze the NYC electricity demand enriched using NOAA weather data for NYC &amp;amp; answer the following questions:
 What effect does date &amp;amp; time play in influencing daily electricity demand in NYC?  What are the Seasonal (daily, hourly, monthly, etc) patterns in the data? Do holidays or events play any role?   How viable are traditional ML algorithms in forecasting Day Ahead Elctricity Demand?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second snippet</title>
      <link>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/snippets/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://satyajitovelil.github.io/snippets/second/</guid>
      <description>This content is in snippets/second/index.md
ls -la </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
